Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Peace Movements TAM.541
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Peace Movements
2007-present
TAM.541
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
49.0 websites and 278.4 GB.
Historically, and today, the Left has played a leading role in peace activism. This has included opposition to wars based on their economic, imperial, racial, and other motivations, opposition to war as inconsistent with social and economic justice, and to war and violence as inherently dehumanizing. Since the development of nuclear weapons, the Left has also opposed their proliferation and rationales for their use. This web archive contains websites for entities opposing war and violence, whether in particular instances or in general, including pacifism, and also includes efforts in support of nuclear disarmament. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl.
Tamiment Library.
Scope and Content Note
This web archive contains websites for entities opposing war and violence, whether in particular instances or in general, including pacifism, and also includes efforts in support of nuclear disarmament. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl.
Related Archival Materials
A list of related Tamiment Library web archives, whose ns2:titles all begin with the prefix "Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left)," can be found at the web page Web Archives from New York University Libraries.
Historical/Biographical Note
Tamiment Library (Labor and the Left) Web Archive: Peace Movements Web Archive was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. This service employs open source web archiving utilities developed by Internet Archive with the support of the The International Internet Preservation Consortium. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The role of the Tamiment Library during this project and thereafter was/is to create topically based archives of websites documenting contemporary and ongoing labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Afghan War, 2001-; Antinuclear movement |z United States.; Antinuclear movement.; Iraq War, 2003-; Peace movements |z United States.; Peace movements.
- Peace Movements
  - 3.11 ACTION NYC, 3/10/2012-
  - A.J. Muste Memorial Institute, 12/22/2008-
  - Alliance for Nuclear Accountability, 5/2/2012-
  - Abolition 2000, 7/12/2011-
  - Antiwar.com, 1/15/2010-
  - AntiWar404, 8/3/2010-
  - Bard International Solidarity Movement, 7/14/2011-
  - Brooklyn for Peace, 3/06/2012-
  - Campaign for Peace and Justice, 7/7/2009-
  - Courage to Resist, 11/17/2009-
  - Daisy Alliance, 2/27/2012-
  - Direct Action to Stop the War (San Francisco Bay Area), 10/25/2009-8/12/2011
  - Education for Peace in Iraq Center, 12/2/2008-
  - Fellowship of Reconcillation, 5/7/2008-
  - Get Peaceful!, 8/1/2010-
  - Granny Peace Brigade, 11/16/2009-
  - iCasualties, Operation Iraqi Freedom, Iraq Coalition Casualty Count, 2/26/2010-
  - Iraq Veterans Against the War, 08/16/2009-
  - Lawyers Committee on Nuclear Policy, 3/2/2012-
  - Muslim Peace Coalition, 5/4/2011-
  - National Campaign for a Peace Tax Fund, 7/14/2011-
  - National Peace Conference, 8/4/2011-
  - National War Tax Resistance Coordinating Committee, 7/10/2011-
  - New Priorities Network, 4/23/2012-
  - Nuclear Age Peace Foundation, 3/5/2012-
  - The Nuclear Resister
  - Nukewatch, 3/01/2012-
  - Pax Christi USA, 08/12/2009-
  - Peace Action, 2/25/2010
  - Peace Action New York State, 2/23/2010-
  - Peace Alliance, 5/3/2012-
  - Peace Brigades International, 2/24/2012-
  - Peaceful Tomorrows Network, 4/26/2012-
  - The Peace Pentagon, 9/25/2009-3/9/2010
  - PeaceSmiths, 10/18/2009-
  - Ploughshares Fund, 2/28/2012-
  - Reaching Critical Will, 3/04/2012-
  - US Peace Council, 2/28/2012-
  - Veterans for Peace, 5/11/2011-
  - Veterans for Peace NY, 12/21/2011-
  - Voices for Creative Nonviolence, 3/04/2012-
  - Voters for Peace, 2/26/2012-
  - War is a Crime, 4/4/2012-
  - War Resisters League, 8/12/2009-
  - Win Without War, 4/23/2012-
  - Women Against War, 7/13/2011-